Khaled BEN HASSEN

Enthusiastic and detail-oriented software engineer graduate with a knack for conceptualizing and delivering elegant, user-friendly solutions. Armed with an extensive understanding of product development life-cycle. Currently targeting an Entry-Level opportunity in web development where experience with learned skills will be further developed and utilized.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2020 -Jan 2021 Web developer (Intern)

Sourceamax | Grenoble office, France

- Worked alongside project manager to process the migration of an online survey tool made available to the company's customers in SaaS mode.
- Developed a graphical redesign using VueJs and it's ecosystem with a focus on obtaining user-friendly interfaces.
- Updated analysis modules and the restitution of data in real time.
- Tested and integrated multiple modern Business Intelligence technologies.
- Collected and filtered data from internal IT systems and external sources, prepared it for analysis, and customized queries against the data in order to create data visualizations.
- Exploited open-source repositories with the aim of Integrating a Python-ColdFusion bridge executing the required Python libraries (such as Pandas,Bokeh) in company's ColdFusion servers.

<u>Technologies background</u>: ColdFusion 18, Python 3, Pandas, VueJs, VuetifyJs, Microsof SQL Server, Power BI, Qlik Sense, Zoho Analytics, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows Server 2012.

Aug 2019 -Feb 2020 Web developer (Part-time)

MEDCOM PROD | Sousse, Tunisia

- Contributed to multiple software projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from design to implementation and delivery.
- Developed new software functionalities, ensuring that clients' vision and requirements were met.
- Redesigned company's web-based application and added employee of the month functionality.

<u>Technologies background</u>: PHP (Laravel, WordPress), MariaDB, Sass.

Jun 2019 -Aug 2019 PHP developer (Intern)

Advanced Technologies Software (ATS) | Ariana, Tunisia

- Designed and developed a crowdfunding web application.
- Integrated Razorpay payment gateway.
- Developed micro-services and Web Services (incl. REST/SOAP/XML).
- Created visual representation of support received, the classification of initiatives and campaign monitoring.

 $\underline{\textbf{Technologies background}}: \textbf{Code-igniter 3, PHP 5.6, MySQL, REST API, JSON, Bootstrap 3.3.7, CSS3/HTML5}.$

Jun 2018 -Jul 2018 Full stack developer (Intern)

IT GATE | Sousse, Tunisia

- Designed and implemented a MEAN stack chat web application.
- Integrated Facebook, Google and Instagram APIs for registration and other purposes.
- Implemented end-to-end encrypted conversations.

<u>Technologies background</u>: MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJs, Node.js, Socket.io, JSON, Bootstrap, Social Media APIs.



Sousse, Tunisia

\(+(216) 22 84 47 72

 \square

khaled.benhassen@polytechnicien.tn

in linkedin.com/in/khaled-bhassan/

github.com/Klodovskyy

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming languages:

PHP, Java, Python, ColdFusion, C, Scala, Bash.

Web development:

JavaScript, TypeScript, Express.js Node.js, NPM, JSON, XML, REST API, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Webpack, JQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap.

Framework:

Vue.js, React.js, Laravel, Symfony, Codelgniter, Django.

Web service:

REST, SOAP.

Databases:

SQL : Oracle, MySQL , Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL.

NoSQL : Redis, MongoDB.

Containerization/Version control:

Docker, Git.

Software architecture and project management:

MVC, MTV, MVVM, UML, Scrum.

EDUCATION

Sep 2017 - **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

Nov 2020 POLYTECHNIQUE SCHOOL OF SOUSSE | Sousse, Tunisia

<u>Relevant coursework</u>: Operating systems, data structures, microprocessors, web and mobile development, relational databases, computer networks, artificial intelligence.

• Built multiple web apps in scholar projects.

Sep 2015 - INTEGRATED PREPARATORY CYCLE

Jun 2017 POLYTECHNIQUE SCHOOL OF SOUSSE | Sousse, Tunisia

Relevant coursework: Heavy concentration in data structures, mathematics and physics.

2009 - 2013 HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

ABOU KACEM CHEBBI HIGH SCHOOL | Mahdia, Tunisia

• Bachelor of Science, Computer Science.

A FEW FREELANCE PROJECTS

RentArea: Designed and developed a user friendly online booking system enabling individuals to rent cars, bikes,

and motorcycles.

Technologies: Laravel 5.4, MySQL, Bootstrap, jQuery, Flatpickr.

E-retail: Contributed to the build of an e-commerce website to buy/sell, rent and exchange various products

online.

Technologies: Symfony 3.4, HTML, Twig, Doctrine, Bootstrap, Redis, MVC.

 $\textbf{Programmy:} \ \textbf{Developed a platform enabling registered users to make suggestions and connections for various}$

events (camping, parties, carpooling, etc...).

<u>Technologies</u>: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ASSOCIATIONS

Local Training Team LTT @ Aiesec Tunisia | 2015-2017 :

• Interviewed and trained the new members along with the LTT team.

Vice president @ Google Club Polytechnique School of Sousse | 2016-2018 :

- Organized and participated in regional and national coding contests.
- Taught web development and music editing.

Member @ Tunisian Association for the Future of Science and Technology ATAST | 2011-2015 :

• Been affiliated with a young scientists association applying their imagination and their creativity to technology innovations.

INTERESTS

- Blockchain and cryptocurrency trading
- Cyber security
- Data science
- Music composition

KEY PERSONAL ASSETS

- Creativity and imagination
- Time management
- Team player
- Excellent communication skills

LINGUISTIC KNOWLEDGE

Arabic

Native Proficiency

English

Full Professional Proficiency

French

Full Professional Proficiency

German

Elementary Proficiency